<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://yaolinge.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://yaolinge.github.io/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en" /><updated>2023-07-20T11:45:15+02:00</updated><id>https://yaolinge.github.io/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Yaolin’s Profile</title><subtitle>Yaolin&apos;s personal webpage. Based on [*folio](https://github.com/bogoli/-folio) design.
</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Topptur in Norway</title><link href="https://yaolinge.github.io/blog/2023/topptur/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Topptur in Norway" /><published>2023-04-10T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2023-04-10T00:00:00+02:00</updated><id>https://yaolinge.github.io/blog/2023/topptur</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://yaolinge.github.io/blog/2023/topptur/"><![CDATA[<h2 id="topptur-in-norway">Topptur in Norway</h2>

<p>As I strapped on my skis and took in the crisp mountain air, I couldn’t help but feel grateful for the opportunity to explore Norway’s incredible backcountry. Over the years, I’ve been fortunate enough to take many skiing touring trips through the rugged and stunning landscapes of this Scandinavian country.</p>

<p>My first trip was a bit nerve-wracking. I had never done any backcountry skiing before and was a bit intimidated by the rugged terrain. But with the guidance of an experienced guide and the support of my fellow skiers, I quickly fell in love with the challenge and beauty of skiing through Norway’s wilderness.</p>

<p>We traversed through snow-covered forests, over icy rivers, and up steep mountain passes, taking in breathtaking views of towering peaks and deep valleys. Along the way, we stopped to rest and enjoy hot cocoa and snacks, sharing stories and laughs with one another.</p>

<p>One of the most memorable moments was when we skied up to a cozy cabin in the middle of the mountains. We spent the night there, warming ourselves by the fire and enjoying a hearty meal before snuggling into our sleeping bags for the night. Waking up to the crisp mountain air and a beautiful sunrise was a moment I’ll never forget.</p>

<p>On another trip, we skied through a beautiful national park, catching glimpses of reindeer and arctic foxes as we went. The views were so stunning that we couldn’t resist stopping every few minutes to snap some photos and take it all in.</p>

<p>But it wasn’t just the stunning landscapes that made these trips so special. It was the camaraderie and shared sense of adventure that made each trip an unforgettable experience. Whether we were skiing through a blizzard or enjoying a hot drink by the fire, we always felt a sense of connection with one another and the beautiful natural world around us.</p>

<p>As I look back on my many skiing touring trips through Norway, I feel grateful for the memories and experiences I’ve gained. Each trip was unique and challenging in its own way, but they all shared a sense of beauty and camaraderie that made them truly special.</p>

<iframe width="720" height="540" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/0KXmd3uQ-4Y" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Topptur in Easter holidays]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Jekyll notes</title><link href="https://yaolinge.github.io/blog/2023/jekyll-note/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Jekyll notes" /><published>2023-03-13T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2023-03-13T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>https://yaolinge.github.io/blog/2023/jekyll-note</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://yaolinge.github.io/blog/2023/jekyll-note/"><![CDATA[<h2 id="quick-start">Quick start</h2>
<ul>
  <li><code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">jekyll new my-awesome-site</code> to create a new Jekyll site at ./my-awesome-site.</li>
  <li><code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">cd my-awesome-site</code> to go into the new directory.</li>
  <li><code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">bundle exec jekyll serve</code> to build the site and make it available on a local server.</li>
</ul>

<h3 id="here-are-simplfied-notes-for-jekyll-assisted-blog-webpage-building">Here are simplfied notes for jekyll-assisted blog webpage building.</h3>

<p>:warning: <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">JEKYLL_ENV=production bundle exec jekyll build</code> to build the website in production environment, then copy contents from <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">_site</code> to github.</p>

<p>:warning: Every time after I have modified <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">_config.yml</code> file, then I need to restart the server.</p>

<p>:warning: <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">baseurl=/Blog</code> does not have <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">/</code> in the end</p>

<p>:warning: <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">link: /Blog/</code> then needs to have it in the end in <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">navigation.yml</code>.</p>

<h3 id="jekyll-commands">Jekyll commands</h3>
<ul>
  <li><code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">bundle exec jekyll serve</code> to start the server, but :warning: it is not the production environment, and good for local development.</li>
  <li><code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">JEKYLL_ENV=production bundle exec jekyll build</code> to build the website in production environment, then copy contents from <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">_site</code> to github.</li>
  <li><code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">bundle exec jekyll serve --livereload</code> to start the server with live reload.</li>
  <li><code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">bundle exec jekyll serve --draft</code> to start the server with draft posts.</li>
</ul>

<h3 id="jekyll-plugins">Jekyll plugins</h3>
<ul>
  <li>How to change theme:
    <ul>
      <li>Go to <a href="https://rubygems.org/">rubygems.org</a> and search <strong>jekyll-theme</strong> for the theme you want to use.</li>
      <li>Add the theme to your <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">Gemfile</code> such as <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">gem "jekyll-theme-hacker"</code> and run <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">bundle install</code>.</li>
      <li>Add <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">theme: jekyll-theme-hacker</code> to your <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">_config.yml</code> file.</li>
      <li>Run <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">bundle exec jekyll serve</code> and your site should now be using the theme you added.</li>
    </ul>
  </li>
</ul>

<h3 id="jekyll-layouts">Jekyll layouts</h3>
<ul>
  <li>How to add a new layout: Create a new file <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">post.html</code> in the <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">_layouts</code> directory with the following front matter:</li>
</ul>

<h3 id="jekyll-styling">Jekyll styling</h3>
<ul>
  <li><code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">&lt;br&gt;</code> for line break.</li>
  <li><code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">&lt;hr&gt;</code> for horizontal line.</li>
</ul>

<h3 id="github-pages">Github pages</h3>
<ul>
  <li>How to launch it on github pages:
    <ul>
      <li>Build the site locally with <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">JEKYLL_ENV=production bundle exec jekyll build</code>.</li>
      <li><code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">git checkout -b gh-pages</code> to create a new branch called <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">gh-pages</code>.</li>
      <li>Copy the contents of the <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">_site</code> directory to the root of the <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">gh-pages</code> branch.</li>
      <li><code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">git push origin gh-pages</code> to push the <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">gh-pages</code> branch to GitHub.</li>
    </ul>
  </li>
</ul>

<h1 id="resources">Resources</h1>
<ul>
  <li><a href="https://maximorlov.com/deploying-to-github-pages-dont-forget-to-fix-your-links/">Explaining permalinks</a></li>
</ul>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[My jekyll learning notes]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Northern Lights</title><link href="https://yaolinge.github.io/blog/2022/northern-lights/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Northern Lights" /><published>2022-09-10T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2022-09-10T00:00:00+02:00</updated><id>https://yaolinge.github.io/blog/2022/northern-lights</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://yaolinge.github.io/blog/2022/northern-lights/"><![CDATA[<p>Long ago, in a land of eternal snow and ice, there lived a tribe of people who had never seen the sun. They had heard stories of it from travelers who passed through their village, but to them, it was nothing more than a myth.</p>

<p>One night, as the villagers sat around their fires, a strange and wondrous thing happened. The sky above them began to shimmer and dance with colors they had never seen before. Shades of green, blue, and purple swirled and twisted above their heads, as if a great wizard was painting the sky.</p>

<p>At first, the villagers were frightened. They had never seen anything like it before and did not know what to make of it. But as they watched, they began to feel a sense of wonder and awe. They realized that this was the sun they had heard about, only it was not a fiery ball of light, but a magnificent display of colors and light.</p>

<p>The people of the tribe gathered together and watched in amazement as the northern lights danced above them. They sang songs and told stories, passing down tales of this mystical phenomenon to future generations.</p>

<p>And so, the northern lights became a symbol of hope and wonder for the people of the village. They knew that even in the midst of the darkest and coldest nights, there was beauty and magic in the world. And as long as the northern lights continued to dance in the sky above them, they knew that they would always have something to marvel at and cherish.</p>

<p><img src="https://yaolinge.github.io/assets/img/nordlys.jpg" alt="Nordlys" width="100%" /></p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="nordlys" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[northern lights]]></summary></entry></feed>